Puneet Nigam

M: +91 9873565410

E: Puneetnigam2000@gmail.com

Seeking leadership challenges in the SAP Solution Delivery function

A well-qualified and expert IT professional with over 15+ years of experience. 5 years of project management experience in project implementations using formal project management methodology, techniques, and tools. Involved in taking challenging Leadership of Projects in ERP and Industry Solution Projects. Experiences in project management, technologies, methodologies, domains, and different knowledge areas.

Area of Expertise

EL (DEDETOE	CORTACIONAL CENTRAL	T
EXPERTISE	CORE MANAGEMENT COMPETENCIES	TECHNICAL EXPERTISE
Project / Account / Delivery Management	Client Management	SAP IS –Utilities (FICA)
SAP Implementations / Support &	 Project Development & Management 	SAP Insurance (FSCD)
Maintenance / Upgrades	-	SAP PSCD
Pre-sales / Operations / Vendor	Quality Control	SAP FICO and Most
Management / Training & Mentoring	Team Leadership	Functional Areas.
Experience in Agile methodology & frameworks such as Scrum,	Strategic Planning	Business Impact Analysis. • SAP Security.
fundamentals of iterative and incremental development	 Problem Troubleshooting & Resolution 	Application Development and Management
Knowledge of agile tools such as JIRA, confluence etc	Training & Development	SAP Solution Manager,
	Account Management	ASAP and, Agile methodologies
	 Global Delivery Onsite- Offshore model 	SAP Activate
		Certified SAP S4/HANA (SAP S/4HANA for Financial Accounting Associates (SAP S/4HANA 2021)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Organization	Designation	Duration	
Capgemini UK	Delivery Manager	08.05.2018- 08.10.2023	
SAP India	Service Delivery Manager	29.02.2016- 30.03.2018	
Tech Mahindra Ltd, India	Project Manager	02.07.2015 – 23.02.2016	
SAP GDC, India	Solution Architect	18.01.2012- 1-07-2015	
IBM Global Services Ltd. India	Senior Advance Consultant	08.08.2005 – 31.12.2011	
HCL Technologies Limited, India	Senior Consultant	10.11.2003- 05.08.2005	

Siemens Information Systems Ltd. India	Consultant	05.02.2003- 20.06.2003
Exl Services Ltd, India	Account Executive	23.07.2001-24.01.2003

PROJECT DETAILS

Company	Clients	Project	Roles & Responsibilities	Key achievements
Capgemini Plc UK	HMRC Worthing UK	SAP TRM/PSCD implementation for ITSA Regime	End to End Project Management and BAU engagement for Service Transition. Client/Stakeholder Management & Communication. Team Management, Onshore/Offshore model. Governance Model Setup. RAID Management. Internal & Client Project Reporting. Change Management. Escalation Management. Budget Management. Supplier Management	Team Spirit Award 2019/20/21/22, for successfully leading a multi- million value, complex implementation on time and budget with high customer satisfaction
SAP ATS -India	MSG Insurance, Singapore Ageas Insurance, Singapore	SAP FSCD, Support, Change and Enhancement	End-to-end service management from Development to Transition to Support. In a multi-vendor environment with rigorous SLA in a 24/7 operation. Overall Transition Planning including definition of SLAs. Define Support Processes/ON CALL Support. Program/Project Governance Budget Management RAID Management Team Management Change Management Change Management Customer Communication Escalation Management Resource Management & Forecasting Overall Business Reporting Continuous Service Improvement. Lead the Weekly/Monthly Service Review Meetings	Delivery Excellence Award 2017, for management of a critical and complex BU, bringing its SLAs from Red to Green. New business generated up to ~\$2 million in 2016-2018 by identification of new business opportunities as a part of Service improvements
Tech Mahindra India- Project Manager	KMD Denmark	SAP - PSCD Implementation	Developing work plans, and documentation, managing deadlines and coordinating project team and sub-team activities. Directly involving and managing all aspects of the project life cycle and working with IT partners to	

			oversee all phases of a project. Rigorously involved in identifying and managing scope to ensure commitments are achieved within the agreed time, cost, and quality parameters with a focus on delivering the business benefits. Identifies and analyses constraints and assumptions and develops time and cost reserves for the project. Worked with team members to resolve variances from the project management plan. Preparing and communicating periodic project status reports, issues, and changes and tailoring them to the needs of the stakeholders. Maintains control over the project by measuring performance and determining if changes are needed. Managing and co-ordinating stakeholders and teams engaged in project work Manage and define project baselines, change control, and finalize scope baseline, with approval from the steering committee and key stakeholders. Prepare Quality checklist, and matrix to fulfil all deliverables that are being completed to be defined expectations. All change and issue logs are properly documented, impact analysed and get approval through a proper change control system. Follow Agile/ASAP methodology with best practice scenario	
SAP GDC- INDIA, Solution Architect	KIIT University-India General Insurance Company, India Queensland Motorways, Australia) Gold Coast City Council, Australia)	SAP TRM/PSCD implementation for ITSA Regime	 To identify, design, and implement creative business solutions and technology solutions for the Company based on the requirement. Involved in AS-IS and To-BE workshops and find out the GAP analysis. Provided best optimize the best solution for the business process into SAP. Analyse business cases, requirements, and future growth plans with key stakeholders. As solution Architecture providing the design and enhancement of the solution for the optimized solution. 	

			 Prepare and Review SOW for the project preparation phase. Involve in Preparing all Traceability and RICWEF documents. involved in Functional System Specification (FSS) and technical System Specification (TSS). Prepare and/or coordinate high-level design documents (HLD) & detailed level design documents (DLD).
IBM-Senior Consultant SAP FICA/FICO/SD	Torrent Power, Surat India	SAP IS- UTILITY Roll out – Surat	 Business process design and System Configuration. Process gap analysis and Solutions.
	Torrent Power, Ahmedabad, India	SAP IS- UTILITY Implementation SAP FICO - Public Sector Implementation for 5 councils.	 Functional Specification for Customer Enhancement. Managing the FICO developments & expediting the
	Southwest One SAP Implementation – BRISTOL UK		same for delivery to clients at a scheduled time. Developed many reports through Report Painter related
	Geometric Software Solutions Ltd (GSSL)	SAP R/3 FICO with cProjects implementation.	to customers, and vendors.
	Grasim Cement , Hyd, India	SAP ECC5 FICO implementation.	

Education Details

- M.B.A. (Finance/IT), from IISE LUCKNOE Affiliated with AICTE.
- M.Com. (Master of Commerce), from Kanpur University.
- B. Sc. (Maths), from Lucknow University.

Training and Certifications

S. No	Title	Location	Organized by	Duration
1	SAP FI 4.6C	India	Sapient College, New Delhi	5 Weeks
2	SAP FI/CO	India	Siemens Information Systems Ltd.	1 Week
3	SAP FI/CA	India	HCL Technologies Ltd.	2 Weeks
4	PMP (internal)	India	Tech Mahindra, Bangalore	1 Week
5	First-level Scrum Master certification (CSM)		SCRUM University	1 day
6	SAP S/4HANA for Financial Accounting Associates (SAP S/4HANA 2021)		Capgemini UK	5weeks